## Chong Han Chua

johncch@outlook.com / +1 (412) 519-2749

www: https://fifthrevision.com gh: https://github.com/johncch

Hello

I've spent the last 10+ years exploring, building and managing digital products in both web and mobile. I believe that successful software has to be a cross-functional collaboration across all disciplines, from marketing to design to engineering.

Experience

Product Designer Honeycomb, since Oct 2017

Honeycomb is a series-A funded company that makes a data visualization tool that helps software engineers diagnose problems and debug software services with production data.

As the first and only designer, I established the design practice at Honeycomb. I've redesigned the product to be approachable and easy to use at the same time moving the product forward in a competitive marketplace. My work spans all aspect of design at the company, from planning, scoping and feature execution to marketing collaterals to design operations such as building out a visual and design system and components library.

Co-founder Echlo, Jan 2016 - Oct 2017

Cofounded Echlo to explore novel scenarios with real-time and persistent location sharing within social groups. The first product we shipped was an iOS app Pulse. I was responsible for product planning, brand, UI and UX concerns and implemented the iOS and web applications.

Senior Program Manager Microsoft, Oct 2011 - Dec 2015

UX product owner during the Hotmail to Outlook.com redesign/rebrand and was responsible for many of the features in the web UI, including compose, files, design and inbox management. The current version of the web client still retains most of the UX decisions that were made then.

Later, I led efforts to generate new mobile app ideas for Office 365, and eventually saw the conception to ship effort of Twist, a Microsoft Garage app tapping into photo communications.

Self-employed Since 2000

Performed design and development work for organizations of all sizes. Recent projects included consulting for Escher Reality, an YC-funded AR startup (since acquired) where I designed single and multi-user AR experiences and authored their first AR Human Interface Guidelines. In another project for Phyn, as part of making the device feel responsive and smart, I defined and designed the interactive animations for the device's LED panel.

Software Engineer IBM, Aug 2008 - July 2010

Worked on an enterprise project for the largest telco company in Singapore delivering ticketing flow and customer service software for both browsers and touch-screen kiosks.

Education

Masters in Human-Computer Interaction Carnegie-Mellon University, 2011

B.Eng (Hons.) in Electrical Engineering National University of Singapore, 2008